<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <meta>
    <id>building-this-portfolio</id>
    <title>Building This Portfolio</title>
    <subtitle>A meta case study on creating a role-agnostic portfolio</subtitle>
    <client>Personal Project</client>
    <role>Content Designer &amp; Developer</role>
    <thumbnail>/assets/images/building-this-site-card.jpg</thumbnail>
    <teaser>How I designed a format-based navigation system to present work across Content Design, Technical Writing, and Narrative roles.</teaser>
    <tags>
      <tag>Content Design</tag>
      <tag>Case Study</tag>
      <tag>Information Architecture</tag>
      <tag>Content Strategy</tag>
    </tags>
  </meta>

  <summary>
    This case study explores the decisions behind building this portfolio site. As a multidisciplinary writer spanning Content Design, Technical Writing, and Narrative/Game Writing, I needed a portfolio structure that could adapt to different hiring contexts without pigeonholing my work into a single specialty.
  </summary>

  <content>
    <section>
      <heading>Challenge</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p><em>[Placeholder - Nick to write]</em></p>
          <p>Creating a role-agnostic portfolio for a multidisciplinary writer. The challenge was presenting work that spans Content Design, Technical Writing, and Narrative/Game Design without forcing visitors to choose a professional identity before exploring.</p>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>

    <section>
      <heading>Information Architecture Decisions</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p><em>[Placeholder - Nick to write]</em></p>
          <p>Why format-based taxonomy (Case Studies vs. Individual Samples) over role-based categories. The distinction is about depth and presentation style, not professional specialty:</p>
          <ul>
            <li><strong>Case Studies:</strong> Deep dives into content decisions based on specific objectives, showcasing cross-collaboration and strategic thinking</li>
            <li><strong>Individual Samples:</strong> Focused pieces demonstrating craft in a particular format without full project context</li>
          </ul>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>

    <section>
      <heading>Technical Choices</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p><em>[Placeholder - Nick to write]</em></p>
          <p>Technology stack and why these choices support the content goals:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Eleventy 2.0 static site generator</li>
            <li>XML-based content model (not Markdown)</li>
            <li>Nunjucks templating</li>
          </ul>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>

    <section>
      <heading>Navigation Design</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p><em>[Placeholder - Nick to write]</em></p>
          <p>How the tag system works for discovery while categories handle wayfinding:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>18 tags across 4 categories for filtering (desktop only)</li>
            <li>Category landing pages for mobile users who don't have desktop tag filters</li>
            <li>localStorage for nav state persistence</li>
          </ul>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>

    <section>
      <heading>Content Strategy</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p><em>[Placeholder - Nick to write]</em></p>
          <p>The distinction between case studies and samples, and how each type serves different evaluation needs for hiring managers.</p>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>

    <section>
      <heading>Responsive Considerations</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p><em>[Placeholder - Nick to write]</em></p>
          <p>How the portfolio adapts between desktop (with tag filters) and mobile (nav-only browsing), and why category landing pages are critical for mobile users.</p>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>
  </content>

  <outcomes>
    <outcome>Created a navigation structure that adapts to different hiring contexts</outcome>
    <outcome>Designed a tag system that lets work speak for itself across specialties</outcome>
    <outcome>Built an accessible, responsive experience that works on all devices</outcome>
  </outcomes>
</project>
