<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ============================================================================
     BLOG POST: Rules are Ok, Constraints are Better
     ============================================================================
     A personal story about a 7th grade writing workshop that illustrates
     the difference between rules and constraints in creative work.

     KEY FEATURES IN THIS POST:
     - Lead paragraph (larger opening text)
     - Personal narrative from childhood
     - Pull quote (highlighted key insight)
     - Callout box (practical constraint exercise)
     - Professional application of the concept
     ============================================================================ -->
<post>
  <meta>
    <!-- REQUIRED: Unique identifier used in URL (/blog/constraints-are-better/) -->
    <id>constraints-are-better</id>

    <!-- REQUIRED: Post title displayed in headers and listings -->
    <title>Rules are Ok, Constraints are Better</title>

    <!-- REQUIRED: Publication date (YYYY-MM-DD format) -->
    <date>2026-01-27</date>

    <!-- AUTHOR INFORMATION -->
    <author>Nicholas Galinski</author>
    <authorPhoto>/assets/images/author-nick.jpg</authorPhoto>
    <authorBio>Multidisciplinary writer specializing in technical documentation, UX content, and creative storytelling. Former English teacher who brings narrative craft to every form of writing.</authorBio>

    <!-- HERO IMAGE (Featured visual at top of post) -->
    <heroImage>/assets/images/blog/multidisciplinary-writer-hero.jpg</heroImage>
    <heroAlt>A prism showing ideas coming in and various types of story content coming out</heroAlt>

    <!-- THUMBNAIL IMAGE (Square image for blog listing cards) -->
    <thumbnailImage>/assets/images/blog/constraints-thumbnail.jpg</thumbnailImage>
    <thumbnailAlt>Visual representation of creative constraints enabling better writing</thumbnailAlt>

    <!-- EXCERPT (Used in blog listings and previews) -->
    <excerpt>A personal story about a 7th grade writing workshop reveals why constraints often produce better writing than unlimited freedom.</excerpt>

    <!-- FEATURED FLAG (Makes this post prominent on blog index) -->
    <featured>true</featured>

    <!-- TAGS (Categories for organization and filtering) -->
    <tags>
      <tag>Writing</tag>
      <tag>Constraints</tag>
      <tag>Professional Development</tag>
    </tags>
  </meta>

  <!-- POST CONTENT
       ======================================================================
       Content is wrapped in CDATA to allow HTML/CSS without XML parsing issues.

       AVAILABLE CSS CLASSES:
       - .lead           : Larger opening paragraph
       - .pullquote      : Centered, emphasized quote (use <blockquote>)
       - .callout        : Highlighted box for important content
       - <figure>        : Images with captions
       ====================================================================== -->
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
      <p class="lead">The first creative writing workshop I ever attended was in the 7th grade.</p>

      <p>One of the high school English teachers had organized a two-day "Writer's Conference" in the school library in an effort to drum up interest in creative writing electives. While many of the other kids had signed up just to get out of their other classes for two days, a handful of other students and I were there because we knew exactly what we were getting into.</p>

      <p>Four years earlier in the 3rd grade, our unit on creative writing had led to something really fun. Our school had a "publishing center", where we'd write our story and draw it on a series of pages, then we'd go down to this little nook near the library. The assistant librarian would machine-laminate all the pages and then attach them with plastic binding.</p>

      <p>Seeing the story I had written, "The Super Bros" (essentially an SNES Super Mario Brothers fan-fiction that replaced Mario and Luigi with myself and two friends) bound together in a professional form had hooked me. <em>You mean I can create things, and other people can read them for enjoyment?</em> I thought.</p>

      <p>Around this same time at home, my father had just finished reading me <em>The Hobbit</em>, and my sister, another talented writer, had read me a chapter of the YA novel she was writing. My imagination was not only constructing a tower of possibility, but reinforcing it with the stories I was exposed to.</p>

      <p>A lack of strong creative writing instruction after the third grade had landed me in a place where I just wanted to write what I wanted to write. So, during the 7th grade Writer's Conference, when we had a choice of sessions to attend, I naturally picked "Freeform Fiction" for my morning, while my afternoon session was chosen based on the instructor: My former 6th grade science teacher, who was an accomplished children's author.</p>

      <p>The morning session was run by an English teacher that was not particularly passionate about creative writing, if I had to assess it in retrospect. In that session, we were asked to write two creative paragraphs that could be the start of a fiction story. We would then share stories and discuss feedback.</p>

      <p>That's when I faced what all writers dread: A blank page and nothing to write. It wasn't that I had no ideas, it was that I had too many ideas. The anxiety of my fellow peers analyzing my choices and the lack of prompt direction left me watching the clock and doodling in the margins. As every 5 minute segment of time passed, the doodling gave me more guilt as no words appeared on the page. Finally, with 15 minutes left, I ended up writing so fast my hand hurt. The subject? Two poorly written paragraphs about a boy bored in a library. I'd thrown it together so fast that I had ink smears along the outer edge of my pinky down to my wrist.</p>

      <p>I didn't feel proud about the work at all. It was something I wrote just to get through the session. I guess the good thing about it being 7th grade is that kids are still innocently honest at that age, but also didn't really know much about writing craft yet. The feedback I got? Something about liking it. "It was good". Nothing helpful, but would it really have mattered? I knew it was bad.</p>

      <p>After lunch, it was time for the second session. While I don't remember its name, I do remember its focus was on perspective and setting. Kids have a tendency of writing stories in first person, and this was challenging us to write in third person. Not only did we have to write in third person, but we had to put a character in the scene and describe where they were. The limitations? We couldn't ever explicitly say where they were and couldn't use the name of any landmarks. No Empire State Building or Pyramids of Giza. Our peers would then have to guess where the setting was based on our writing.</p>

      <p>This time, I was writing from the word "go". I started describing a very specific hallway in our school, a depressing stretch of yellowed-linoleum floors that led to a corner where an open window in a nearby classroom resulted in trash cyclones of Warhead wrappers and dust bunnies. I didn't have to think of where this story could go later, or even who the main character was. I just had to write within the parameters I was given.</p>

      <p>Constraints.</p>

      <p>It was exciting when someone in my group had a "lightbulb" moment and said "I know exactly where that is!"</p>

      <figure>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/constraints-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Visual representation of creative constraints enabling better writing">
      </figure>

      <p>The difference in the two assignments was not, as it turns out, my creativity. It was not my age, or my talent, or even my willingness to work. It was the number of decisions I was being asked to make in silence. In the morning session, "freeform" sounded like permission, but it behaved like pressure. Any genre. Any setting. Any character. Any voice. Any beginning. It was an infinite menu with a timer running, and my mind did what it always does when it cannot find a boundary to push against. It stalled, then panicked, then produced something that felt like a concession rather than a piece of writing.</p>

      <p>In the afternoon session, the scope collapsed into something smaller and sharper: third person, a setting rendered through description, no landmark names, and a room full of readers trying to solve the same puzzle. I did not have to invent a universe. I had to make a particular place legible without saying its name. I had to choose details with intention. I had to earn recognition. The constraints did not make the assignment easier. They made it writable.</p>

      <h2>Rules and constraints are not the same thing</h2>

      <p>When people talk about "rules" in writing, they usually mean the craft advice we accumulate over time: avoid clichés, vary your sentence structure, show rather than tell, cut the throat-clearing, find the verb that does the work. Rules are often useful, especially early on, because they name patterns and prevent obvious failure modes. They are guardrails, and guardrails matter when you are moving fast or learning the road.</p>

      <p>Constraints do something different. Constraints do not primarily tell you what to avoid. They tell you what you are doing. They define the container, the target, and the limits of the field, which means they also define where the creative energy goes. A rule can improve the sentence you were already going to write. A constraint is what helps you write a sentence at all.</p>

      <blockquote class="pullquote">
        A blank page is not freedom. It is an obligation to decide everything.
      </blockquote>

      <p>This is why "just write" feels like a cruel mantra for so many writers. It assumes the obstacle is motivation, when the obstacle is often scope. Total freedom is expensive. Every option you keep available costs attention, and attention is the currency writing runs on. Constraints spend that currency for you, narrowing the decision space until momentum becomes possible. They turn writing from an existential question into a solvable task, which is a quieter and more reliable form of inspiration than most people want to admit.</p>

      <h2>Constraints are how professionals write every day</h2>

      <p>The irony is that most professional writing is constraint-driven by default, even when it does not look like a creative writing exercise. Technical writing is built on realities that do not bend: the product does what it does, the audience needs what it needs, and the content has to move a reader from confusion to clarity without wasting their time. You can have style, you can have voice, you can have rhythm, but you cannot ignore function. That is a constraint, and it is also a gift, because it tells you what the work is for.</p>

      <p>UI and UX writing compress those pressures further. The interface gives you a tiny stage and asks you to land the beat anyway. Sometimes you have room for two words. Sometimes you have one line to explain why something failed to someone who is already frustrated. Sometimes the sentence must be clear, human, brand-aligned, and legally safe while also fitting inside a component that was never designed with language in mind. That is not creative deprivation. It is a high-skill environment where every word has to earn its space, and where constraints are not an obstacle to craft but the condition that makes craft visible.</p>

      <p>This is where the distinction starts to matter in practice. Your style guide supplies your rules: terminology, capitalization, tone boundaries, the preferences that keep the writing consistent. Your frameworks supply your constraints: templates, content models, patterns for errors and empty states, the structural decisions that determine what kind of problem you are solving. Rules keep the writing clean. Constraints keep the writing moving.</p>

      <h2>A constraint you can borrow</h2>

      <p>If you want to feel this shift in your own work, you do not need a workshop leader or a prompt generator. You can build the container yourself, and the container can be small enough to fit inside one sitting.</p>

      <div class="callout">
        <p><strong>Try writing one paragraph under these constraints:</strong></p>
        <ul>
          <li>Keep it between 140 and 180 words</li>
          <li>Do not use any proper nouns</li>
          <li>Describe a place as if the reader has been there before</li>
          <li>End with a sentence that begins with "So."</li>
        </ul>
      </div>

      <p>The point is not that these specific limits are sacred. The point is that the limits force choices, and choices are what turn "I should write" into actual language on the page.</p>

      <p>Once the paragraph exists, you can loosen the constraints, expand, add texture, revise for voice, break the rules you need to break. That order matters. Constraints are not a permanent cage. They are the scaffolding that lets you build something sturdy enough to refine.</p>

      <h2>Why constraints produce better writing</h2>

      <p>Constraints do not guarantee quality, but they increase the odds of finishing, and finishing is the prerequisite for everything else. They reduce the number of decisions competing for your attention. They create a clearer definition of success than "make it good." They shift the emotional stakes from identity to execution, which makes it easier to take risks without feeling like you are being judged as a person. Most importantly, they give you friction. They give your mind something to push against, which is often what the creative part of you has been waiting for all along.</p>

      <p>Rules are ok. Constraints are better.</p>
    ]]>
  </content>
</post>
