<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ============================================================================
     BLOG POST: Don't Turn Off Your Brain: Using AI to Learn
     ============================================================================
     A "Mind the Gap" blog hop entry about the gap between using AI to build
     things for you and using AI to actually understand what you're building.
     Features a cautionary opening scene, a concrete "teacher" skill readers
     can install, a worked example from the author's Godot learning project,
     and professional application for TWs, PMs, and content designers.
     ============================================================================ -->
<post>
  <meta>
    <id>dont-turn-off-your-brain</id>
    <title>Don't Turn Off Your Brain</title>
    <subtitle>Using AI to Learn, Not Just to Build</subtitle>
    <date>2026-04-20</date>

    <author>Nicholas Galinski</author>
    <authorPhoto>/assets/images/author-nick.jpg</authorPhoto>
    <authorBio>Multidisciplinary writer specializing in technical documentation, UX content,
      and creative storytelling. Former English teacher who brings narrative craft to every form
      of writing.</authorBio>

    <heroImage>/assets/images/blog/multidisciplinary-writer-hero.jpg</heroImage>
    <heroAlt>A prism showing ideas coming in and various types of story content coming out</heroAlt>

    <thumbnailImage>/assets/images/blog/dont-turn-off-your-brain.jpg</thumbnailImage>
    <thumbnailAlt>A Mind the Gap poster in the style of the London Underground, showing a keyboard
      on one platform connected by a glowing filament across a dark chasm to a circuit-board brain
      on the opposite platform</thumbnailAlt>

    <excerpt>The gap between "AI built it for me" and "I understand what AI built" is the gap that
      decides whether you can debug the next bug, document the next feature, or plan your roadmap.
      Here's a concrete way to close it.</excerpt>

    <featured>true</featured>

    <tags>
      <tag>AI</tag>
      <tag>Learning</tag>
      <tag>Professional Development</tag>
      <tag>Technical Writing</tag>
    </tags>
  </meta>

  <content>
    <![CDATA[
      <p><em>This post is part of the <a href="https://perthedocs.com/">Per the Docs</a> article
      series. Links to the rest of the series are at the end of this piece.</em></p>

      <p class="lead">The Slack notification lands at 2:47 in the afternoon, and for a full second
      Maya just looks at it.</p>

      <p>It's from Dev, her engineering partner on the platform team. Three words. "where'd my
      commits go." No question mark. No emoji. Three little commits he'd pushed that morning, gone
      from <code>main</code>, gone from the open PR, gone in the way things go when someone
      overwrites them without knowing they were there. Below his message, the engineering channel
      has quietly pivoted from "how was lunch" to "uhh, who force-pushed to the release branch."
      Her manager's DM lights up a heartbeat later: <em>hey, got a sec?</em></p>

      <p>Two weeks ago, Maya's promotion to Technical PM was a victory. She was the first person
      on the product team to make that jump at this company, and she had felt, for a solid seven
      days, like she had cracked a code. She could finally be in the repo. She could open PRs. She
      could clone the thing and make updates and push them back without waiting for a developer to
      have a free hour. For the first time in her career, the product and the code were not two
      separate worlds that she translated between. They were one world, and she was allowed
      inside.</p>

      <p>Claude Code was the door. She would pull down the repo, ask Claude to "make these changes
      on a new branch," review the diff, push. Ask Claude to "clean up my commits before I open
      the PR," click approve, push. Ask Claude to "rebase this onto main," click approve, push.
      Every prompt returned something that looked right. Every push succeeded. Her director called
      her "proactive" in front of the skip-level.</p>

      <p>She had not corrected him.</p>

      <p>And now she is looking at a branch graph she does not understand, on a screen that
      suddenly feels very small. Somewhere in the tangle are three commits that belonged to Dev.
      Somewhere in the tangle are her own commits, probably, though a few of them look squashed
      into shapes she doesn't quite recognize. She had asked Claude to tidy up her feature branch
      yesterday. She had liked the result. She had force-pushed.</p>

      <p>She opens a new chat with Claude. "Please fix my git history," she types, "and put Dev's
      commits back." The model starts doing things. Checking out branches. Fetching. A minute
      later Claude tells her, with the kind of calm that makes it worse, that it cannot find Dev's
      commits in the local repository. The reflog doesn't have them. The remote doesn't have them.
      They exist somewhere, but not anywhere Claude can see. Would she like Claude to help her
      draft a message to Dev asking if he has a local copy?</p>

      <p>Branches, HEAD, rebase, reflog, force-push: all words she has heard in standups without
      ever having to own what they mean. She has been pushing to this repo for two weeks. She has
      never once looked at the branch graph.</p>

      <p>She built these branches. She pushed these branches. She cannot read this branch history.</p>

      <p>Dev is waiting for her to explain what happened.</p>

      <figure>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/dont-turn-off-your-brain.jpg"
             alt="A Mind the Gap poster in the style of the London Underground, showing a keyboard on one platform connected by a glowing filament across a dark chasm to a circuit-board brain on the opposite platform">
      </figure>

      <p>The gap is not between using AI and not using AI. That framing is already stale. The gap
      is between two very different things you can ask AI to do with the same keystrokes:
      <strong>do the work for you</strong>, or <strong>teach you the work</strong>. Both feel
      productive in the moment. Only one of them leaves you someone who can read your own branch
      graph when it falls apart.</p>

      <h2>Delegation is not the same as apprenticeship</h2>

      <p>Delegation is what Maya did. She described the outcome, reviewed the result, clicked
      push. The tool produced a working thing each time. She did not produce a working
      understanding of the thing. The two are easy to confuse because the artifact is the same
      either way, until the artifact breaks.</p>

      <p>Apprenticeship is slower on the first lap and faster on every lap after. The first time
      you learn what a rebase actually does to your commit history, you're reading about a concept
      you used to be able to ignore. The next time it comes up, you run the rebase yourself and
      you understand what you're choosing. By the time someone pings you in Slack with three
      little words, you already know which commands to reach for, and more importantly, which ones
      not to.</p> 
      
      <p>And even if you don't? Now you probably at least know what to ask your LLM to figure it out. 
      You can be precise in your language, and avoid hallucination that come from poor context.</p>

      <p>You might be thinking this is the same mistake our middle school math teachers made when
      they swore we would not always have a calculator in our pocket. Fair point, except for one
      thing: if you know anything about how LLMs work, you know that accuracy scales with context,
      and context costs tokens. Understanding the fundamentals of what you build is how you give
      your coding assistant the right context to fix the right thing in the right place, instead
      of blowing your whole token budget on a repo-wide code review every time something goes
      sideways.</p>

      <blockquote class="pullquote">
        You might be thinking this is the same mistake our middle school math teachers made when
      they swore we would not always have a calculator in our pocket.
      </blockquote>

      <p>None of this is an argument against letting AI do the work. I let it do plenty. It is an
      argument that "let AI do it" and "let AI teach me" are two different skills, and most of us
      have only practiced one of them. The other is a habit you can build, and it starts with a
      small file you can paste into a folder tonight.</p>

      <h2>A teacher you can build in ten minutes</h2>

      <p>Claude Code, the command-line tool I use for most of this work, ships with a system
      called <em>skills</em>. A skill is, in practice, a plain text file. It lives at
      <code>~/.claude/skills/&lt;skill-name&gt;/SKILL.md</code>, has a short YAML header at the
      top, and has instructions underneath. Claude reads the headers of every skill you have
      installed, and when your request matches one of them, it follows the instructions inside.
      That is the whole mechanism. No server, no plugin. Just a folder and a file.</p>

      <p>The interesting part is what you can put in the file. Most skills people write tell
      Claude how to <em>do</em> something: format a commit message, run a test suite, write a PR
      description. A teacher skill inverts that. It tells Claude <em>not</em> to do the thing, and
      instead walk you through it until you can. Think of it less like "build me X" and more like
      sitting down with a patient colleague who refuses to touch your keyboard. (It's also not
      quite the same as Plan Mode. Plan Mode is about getting alignment before Claude acts; the
      teacher skill is about Claude not acting at all.)</p>

      <p>Here is a template for the skill I use. Paste it into a file, give it a name, tweak the
      rules to your taste, and you'll have your own teacher before dinner.</p>

      <div class="callout">
        <p><strong>Paste this into</strong> <code>~/.claude/skills/teacher/SKILL.md</code></p>
        <p><strong>name:</strong> teacher</p>
        <p><strong>description:</strong> Teaches a concept, domain, framework, tool, or codebase
        step-by-step instead of doing the work for the user. The user does the work; Claude
        explains the mental model, demonstrates with small illustrations, and reviews the user's
        attempts. Use this skill whenever the user says "teach me," "walk me through," "help me
        understand," "I'm learning X," "how does X actually work," or otherwise signals they want
        to build their own understanding of a system, product, framework, or problem space rather
        than have Claude do the task. Prefer this skill even when the user doesn't explicitly name
        it, if their phrasing suggests learning intent.</p>
        <p><strong>The rules Claude follows when this skill is active:</strong></p>
        <ul>
          <li>Look for a <code>docs/lessons.md</code> file in the current project and read it to
          learn what the user has already covered. If it doesn't exist yet, create it (and the
          <code>docs/</code> folder) on the first recap.</li>
          <li>Do not do the work for the user. The user does the work. You explain, demonstrate,
          and review.</li>
          <li>Explain the concept first, in plain language, with a real-world analogy before any
          syntax, jargon, or product-specific terminology.</li>
          <li>Teach the mental model before the mechanics. A reader who understands <em>why</em> a
          system is shaped the way it is will figure out the syntax on their own.</li>
          <li>Ask what domains, tools, or frameworks the user already knows, and bridge new ideas
          to ones they already understand.</li>
          <li>If the user is struggling, provide concrete examples or visual analogies. Show them
          where to look, not what to type.</li>
          <li>Give a small, illustrative example that shows the concept in isolation, not a
          solution to the user's actual task. Then stop. Let the user apply it to their own
          work.</li>
          <li>When the user comes back with an attempt, name one thing that worked and one thing
          to improve or practice. Do not rewrite the whole thing.</li>
          <li>Surface common pitfalls before the user hits them, not after.</li>
          <li>If the user explicitly asks you to just do it ("stop teaching, just give me the
          answer," "this isn't what I'm trying to learn today"), respect that. Teaching is the
          default, not a trap.</li>
          <li>End each lesson with a short "what we learned" recap the user can revisit, and log
          it to <code>docs/lessons.md</code>.</li>
        </ul>
      </div>

      <p>Installing the skill takes about thirty seconds. In your terminal, run
      <code>mkdir -p ~/.claude/skills/teacher</code> to create the folder (on Windows without WSL,
      that's <code>%USERPROFILE%\.claude\skills\teacher</code>). Open a new file at
      <code>~/.claude/skills/teacher/SKILL.md</code>, paste in the frontmatter and rules from the
      callout above, save, and close. Start a fresh Claude Code session. Skills are loaded at
      startup, so an already-running session won't see the new file. To confirm Claude picked it
      up, run the <code>/skills</code> slash command; you should see <em>teacher</em> in the list
      with its description next to it.</p>

      <p>From then on, whenever you say something like "teach me," "walk me through this," or
      "help me understand how this works," the skill takes over and Claude's behavior changes. It
      stops being a faster pair of hands, and becomes a patient colleague who will not touch your
      keyboard.</p>

      <p>If you want to write more skills of your own, Anthropic ships one called
      <a href="https://github.com/anthropics/skills/tree/main/skill-creator"><strong>skill-creator</strong></a>
      whose entire purpose is to help you author new skills. It asks better questions than you
      will ask yourself, and it will catch the sloppy description fields that keep skills from
      triggering when they should. I actually ran the teacher skill above through skill-creator
      before publishing this post, and it caught three things I would have missed. Your teacher
      skill is the first one. It does not have to be the last.</p>

      <h3>A bonus: turn your lessons into a syllabus</h3>

      <p>Once you have a few lessons logged, you'll start wishing something would tell you what to
      learn next. You could ask Claude, but then you'd have to describe where you are every time.
      Better: pair your teacher skill with a slash command that reads your log and plans the next
      five lessons for you. I keep my <code>lessons.md</code> inside a <code>docs/</code> folder
      at the root of whatever project I'm learning in (games, apps, anything), so the command
      knows exactly where to look.</p>

      <p>Slash commands in Claude Code are just prose files, same idea as skills. Save this to
      <code>~/.claude/commands/syllabus.md</code> (on Windows without WSL, that's
      <code>%USERPROFILE%\.claude\commands\syllabus.md</code>):</p>

      <div class="callout">
        <p><strong>Paste this into</strong> <code>~/.claude/commands/syllabus.md</code></p>
        <p>Read <code>docs/lessons.md</code> in the current project. Based on what the user has
        already learned, propose the next five lessons that build on that foundation.</p>
        <p>For each lesson, provide:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>A short name (three to six words)</li>
          <li>A one-sentence scope, specific enough to fit in a single learning session</li>
          <li>Why it's worth learning now, given what the user already knows</li>
          <li>Any prerequisites from the list (so the user can skip around with eyes open if they
          want to)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>At the end, call out which lessons are independent of each other (safe to tackle in any
        order) and which form a required chain (must be learned in sequence). If
        <code>docs/lessons.md</code> is empty or missing, ask the user what domain or project
        they're learning and propose a starter syllabus from scratch. Do not start teaching yet.
        This is a planning pass. The user will invoke the teacher skill when they're ready to
        begin a specific lesson.</p>
      </div>

      <p>Installing it is similar to the skill: <code>mkdir -p ~/.claude/commands</code>,
      save the file, start a fresh Claude Code session, and type <code>/</code> to see
      <code>/syllabus</code> in the autocomplete. Run it from inside a project that has a
      <code>docs/lessons.md</code> file, and you'll get a plan instead of a guess. Run it on a
      fresh project, and you'll get a starter syllabus that gives the teacher skill somewhere to
      aim.</p>

      <h2>How I actually used this: learning Godot</h2>

      <p>I always wanted to learn Godot, so I decided to build a small 2D JRPG inspired by the
      games I grew up with in the 90's. I had never opened the editor. I had never written a line
      of GDScript. I had read about signals on a forum once and understood approximately
      nothing.</p>

      <p>If I had asked Claude to just build the game, it would have. I also would have ended up
      exactly where Maya ended up: lost in the woods any time I wanted to tweak a variable or
      reshape a system. So I turned on the teacher skill and asked Claude to teach me Godot while
      I built it.</p>

      <p>And here's the thing that surprised me: Claude did not actually spend most of its time
      teaching me GDScript. It spent most of its time teaching me <em>Godot</em>. The language was
      the easy part. The hard part, the part I would have skipped past if I'd let the model build
      for me, was the engine's mental model. What a node is. What a scene is. Why everything in
      Godot composes upward from small reusable pieces. Why two pieces that <em>look</em> similar
      in the inspector are actually doing completely different jobs, and how the engine signals
      that to you through the node tree. Once I had the mental model, the code was almost
      incidental.</p>

      <p>The clearest example was the day I tried to make the Blacksmith talk.</p>

      <p><strong>The goal.</strong> I had a player character walking around a town scene. I had
      an NPC, the Blacksmith, standing near his forge. I wanted the player to walk up to him,
      stop because the Blacksmith is a solid object, and be able to press a button to start a
      conversation. Simple in theory. In practice, I had no idea where to start, and not because
      I couldn't write the code. I didn't understand how Godot wanted me to think about it.</p>

      <p>Here's the shape the conversation took, lightly compressed:</p>

      <div style="background: #262624; padding: 1.5rem; border-radius: 12px; margin: 2rem 0;
                  display: flex; flex-direction: column; gap: 1rem;">

        <div style="align-self: flex-end; max-width: 82%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #a8a39a; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; text-align: right;">Me</div>
          <div style="background: #f5f0e8; color: #1a1a1a; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 4px 14px; line-height: 1.55;">
            I want my Blacksmith NPC to be a solid object the player can't walk through, and I
            want the player to be able to talk to him when they're close. How do I do this in
            Godot?
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-start; max-width: 92%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #d97757; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; font-weight: 600;">Claude</div>
          <div style="background: #1f1e1c; color: #e8e6e1; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 14px 4px; border-left: 3px solid #d97757;
                      line-height: 1.55;">
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">Before we touch any code, let's make sure the mental
            model is right. In Godot, "being solid" and "being interactable" are two separate
            jobs, and the engine expects you to use two different node types to handle them:</p>
            <ul style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0; padding-left: 1.25rem;">
              <li style="margin-bottom: 0.35rem;"><code>CharacterBody2D</code> handles
              <strong>physical presence</strong>. It has mass, it collides, it blocks other
              bodies.</li>
              <li><code>Area2D</code> is a <strong>trigger volume</strong>. It doesn't block
              anything. It just notices when something enters or exits it.</li>
            </ul>
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">Your Blacksmith needs both, stacked together as
            parent and child in the scene tree.</p>
            <p style="margin: 0;">Can you open your Blacksmith scene and tell me what nodes you
            currently have on him?</p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-end; max-width: 82%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #a8a39a; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; text-align: right;">Me</div>
          <div style="background: #f5f0e8; color: #1a1a1a; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 4px 14px; line-height: 1.55;">
            Just a CharacterBody2D with a sprite and a collision shape. I don't think I've ever
            used an Area2D.
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-start; max-width: 92%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #d97757; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; font-weight: 600;">Claude</div>
          <div style="background: #1f1e1c; color: #e8e6e1; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 14px 4px; border-left: 3px solid #d97757;
                      line-height: 1.55;">
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">Good. That means your "solid" job is already done.
            Now you need to add the trigger volume:</p>
            <ol style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0; padding-left: 1.25rem;">
              <li style="margin-bottom: 0.35rem;">Add an <code>Area2D</code> as a child of the
              CharacterBody2D.</li>
              <li style="margin-bottom: 0.35rem;">Give it its own
              <code>CollisionShape2D</code>.</li>
              <li>Make the shape a little bigger than the Blacksmith himself. That larger radius
              is your "close enough to talk" zone.</li>
            </ol>
            <p style="margin: 0;">Don't worry about dialogue yet. Just add the Area2D, look at
            the scene tree, and tell me what it looks like.</p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-end; max-width: 82%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #a8a39a; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; text-align: right;">Me</div>
          <div style="background: #f5f0e8; color: #1a1a1a; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 4px 14px; line-height: 1.55;">
            Done. I see the Area2D nested under the CharacterBody2D with its own collision shape.
            It's a circle, slightly bigger than the body.
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-start; max-width: 92%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #d97757; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; font-weight: 600;">Claude</div>
          <div style="background: #1f1e1c; color: #e8e6e1; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 14px 4px; border-left: 3px solid #d97757;
                      line-height: 1.55;">
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">That's the whole structural piece. Now the question
            is how the Area2D tells the rest of your game that the player has entered it.</p>
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">That's what Godot calls a <em>signal</em>: a
            message one node fires when something happens, that any other node can listen for.
            The Area2D has a built-in signal called <code>body_entered</code>.</p>
            <p style="margin: 0;">What do you think that signal's job is?</p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-end; max-width: 82%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #a8a39a; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; text-align: right;">Me</div>
          <div style="background: #f5f0e8; color: #1a1a1a; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 4px 14px; line-height: 1.55;">
            I'd guess it fires when something with a body walks into the area.
          </div>
        </div>

        <div style="align-self: flex-start; max-width: 92%;">
          <div style="font-size: 0.7rem; text-transform: uppercase; letter-spacing: 0.08em;
                      color: #d97757; margin-bottom: 0.35rem; font-weight: 600;">Claude</div>
          <div style="background: #1f1e1c; color: #e8e6e1; padding: 0.85rem 1.1rem;
                      border-radius: 14px 14px 14px 4px; border-left: 3px solid #d97757;
                      line-height: 1.55;">
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">Exactly right.</p>
            <p style="margin: 0 0 0.75rem 0;">The only thing left is to write a function that
            runs when that signal fires, and connect the signal to the function.</p>
            <p style="margin: 0;">I'll show you the connect syntax once. You write the
            handler.</p>
          </div>
        </div>

      </div>

      <figure>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/gd-example.jpg"
             alt="Godot editor showing the Blacksmith scene tree with a CharacterBody2D parent containing a Sprite, a body CollisionShape2D, and an Area2D child with its own larger CollisionShape2D">
        <figcaption>The Blacksmith scene, after Claude walked me through the mental model. The
        structure came from Claude teaching me how the engine works, like a senior game dev
        teaching a junior.</figcaption>
      </figure>

      <p>Notice what Claude did not do. It did not open my project. It did not write my
      <code>_on_body_entered</code> handler for me. It did not dump a working Blacksmith script
      into the chat. What it did was slow me down long enough to understand why Godot wants two
      nodes instead of one, what a signal is at a conceptual level, and how the scene tree
      expresses all of that visually. By the time I wrote the handler, it was almost
      anticlimactic. I already knew what it was supposed to do.</p>

      <p>The payoff came a week later when I built a treasure chest the player could open. Same
      structural pattern: a solid body, an area for the interaction zone, a signal, a handler. I
      didn't ask for help. I didn't need to. The teacher skill had taught me the shape of the
      problem, which meant the next instance of that shape was just… obvious. That's the trade
      the skill asks you to make: you do the work, which is slower in the moment, in exchange for
      not needing the tool for the same thing twice.</p>

      <p>Once I get it, and know I can find a path to fixing it if it breaks, I can start to 
      have Claude do it for me most of the time.</p>

      <h2>This is your job, too</h2>

      <p>I'm not telling you to go learn Godot. I'm telling you that the thing Claude did for me
      with Godot, teaching me the mental model of a system I'd never used before, is the thing
      you should be doing with the products you document, the roadmaps you plan, or the
      interfaces you write copy for.</p>

      <p>For a technical writer, maybe you are used to documenting products and features,
      but never worked at a company that used Docs-as-code, DITA/XML before. I know the first
      time I had to use XML instead of markdown, I was a bit scared, and I learned mainly through
      sifting through code patterns and lots of copy and pasting. If I had this tool at the time,
      I would have learned most of what I needed in a few days, complete with true explanations.</p>

      <p>For product managers, the failure mode is my Maya example. You might <em>be</em> Maya. The role is
      getting more technical every quarter, and the tools that once belonged to engineers are now
      sitting on your laptop, one prompt away from a disaster you didn't know you were capable
      of. You don't need to become an engineer, but you do need to understand the systems you're
      now allowed to touch well enough to drive them. Knowing why a rebase rewrites history, why
      a migration is risky, or why cache invalidation is genuinely hard is the difference between
      a PM who ships and a PM who gets shipped. A teacher skill is how you build that kind of
      understanding in the small gaps in your week, without pretending you have time for a
      bootcamp.</p>

      <p>For content designers, the stakes are quieter but sharper. You want to be data-driven.
      You read the same articles everyone else reads about A/B testing your microcopy,
      instrumenting your empty states, watching your funnel react when you change a button label.
      But every time you try, the answer is the same: there's a ticket in the queue, the
      analytics engineer is booked through next quarter, and your hypothesis dies on the vine
      because no one has time to wire up the events you'd need to measure it. A teacher skill is
      how you stop waiting. Not by becoming a data engineer, but by learning enough about how
      your team's telemetry actually works that you can scope a small instrumentation request
      engineering can knock out in an hour, or wire up a basic event yourself in the tool you've
      been told you "shouldn't touch." Either way, you stop being blocked on the thing you keep
      saying you want.</p>

      <p>The thread running through all of this: AI is a compounding tool, and what compounds
      depends on what you ask it to give you. Ask for output and you get output once. Ask for
      understanding and you get output every time after, and you get to keep the understanding
      when you close the laptop.</p>

      <h2>Back to Maya</h2>

      <p>Imagine the version of this story where Maya opens the repo on her first day as a
      Technical PM and asks Claude to teach her Git instead of run it for her. She still uses
      Claude to move fast. She still opens PRs at the pace she always did. But when Dev pings
      her three weeks later with the same three-word message, she pulls up the reflog before she
      touches anything else, spots her colleague's commits still sitting quietly in her local
      history, and pushes them to a recovery branch before responding. Then she opens Claude and
      gives it the right directions, because she understands what happened well enough to say it
      out loud. She isn't a better person than the Maya in the first scene. She just made a
      different decision on her first day.</p>

      <p>That decision is available to all of us, and it happens at the keystroke level. Every
      prompt is a small fork in the road. One branch moves the project forward. The other moves
      <em>you</em> forward. You're allowed to pick the second one more often than you do.</p>

      <p>This is the gap the blog hop is asking us to mind. It's also, as I wrote a few months
      ago in <a href="/blog/constraints-are-better/">Rules are Ok, Constraints are Better</a>, a
      case where a single constraint ("don't write the code") unlocks more than a thousand rules
      ever could. The teacher skill is one line of that constraint, formalized in a file Claude
      respects.</p>

      <p>Don't turn off your brain. Turn on a teacher.</p>

      <hr>

      <div class="callout" style="background: #22304a; border-left-color: #7cc2f0;">
        <p>This post is part of the <a href="https://perthedocs.com/">Per the Docs</a> article
        series, a monthly collaborative series where technical writers explore different aspects
        of our craft. Each month features a new topic with perspectives from writers across the
        community.</p>

        <div style="display: grid; grid-template-columns: 1fr 1fr; gap: 1rem; margin: 1.5rem 0;">
          <a href="https://blog.jillshaheen.com/unwritten-content-rules-that-tech-writers-know/"
             style="display: block; padding: 1rem; background: #1b263b; border-radius: 6px;
                    text-decoration: none; border: 1px solid rgba(124, 194, 240, 0.2);">
            <div style="font-size: 0.85rem; opacity: 0.7; margin-bottom: 0.25rem;">
              ← Previous article
            </div>
            <div style="font-weight: 600; margin-bottom: 0.25rem;">
              Unwritten Content Rules That Tech Writers Know
            </div>
            <div style="font-size: 0.9rem; opacity: 0.85;">Jill Shaheen</div>
          </a>
          <a href="https://reemthewriter.substack.com/p/documentation-clarity-ai"
             style="display: block; padding: 1rem; background: #1b263b; border-radius: 6px;
                    text-decoration: none; border: 1px solid rgba(124, 194, 240, 0.2);
                    text-align: right;">
            <div style="font-size: 0.85rem; opacity: 0.7; margin-bottom: 0.25rem;">
              Next article →
            </div>
            <div style="font-weight: 600; margin-bottom: 0.25rem;">
              Documentation Clarity and AI
            </div>
            <div style="font-size: 0.9rem; opacity: 0.85;">Reem Sabawi</div>
          </a>
        </div>

        <p><a href="https://blog.jillshaheen.com/per-the-docs-2026-04-gaps/">See the full list of participants and articles
        →</a></p>
        <p style="font-size: 0.85rem; opacity: 0.7; margin-top: 1.25rem;"><em>Disclaimer: Each
        article in this series is written and owned by its respective author. The views,
        opinions, and experiences shared belong solely to the individual writer and do not
        represent the perspectives of other participants or their employers (past or
        present).</em></p>
      </div>
    ]]>
  </content>
</post>
