<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ============================================================================
     BLOG POST: I Stopped Trying to Be Just One Kind of Writer
     ============================================================================
     This is a content marketing post about embracing multiple writing roles
     as performance - from technical writing to creative storytelling.

     KEY FEATURES IN THIS POST:
     - Lead paragraph (larger opening text)
     - Pull quote (highlighted key insight)
     - Callout box (list of writing roles)
     - Author information with photo and bio
     - Hero image for visual impact
     - Featured post designation
     ============================================================================ -->
<post>
  <meta>
    <!-- REQUIRED: Unique identifier used in URL (/blog/writers-are-performers/) -->
    <id>writers-are-performers</id>

    <!-- REQUIRED: Post title displayed in headers and listings -->
    <title>Writers are Performers</title>

    <!-- Subtitle displayed below main title -->
    <subtitle>Multidisciplinary Content Design is the Future</subtitle>

    <!-- REQUIRED: Publication date (YYYY-MM-DD format) -->
    <date>2026-01-16</date>

    <!-- AUTHOR INFORMATION -->
    <author>Nicholas Galinski</author>
    <authorPhoto>/assets/images/author-nick.jpg</authorPhoto>
    <authorBio>Multidisciplinary writer specializing in technical documentation, UX content, and creative storytelling. Former English teacher who brings narrative craft to every form of writing.</authorBio>

    <!-- HERO IMAGE (Featured visual at top of post) -->
    <heroImage>/assets/images/blog/multidisciplinary-writer-hero.jpg</heroImage>
    <heroAlt>Theater stage with spotlight representing different writing performance roles</heroAlt>

    <!-- THUMBNAIL IMAGE (Square image for blog listing cards) -->
    <thumbnailImage>/assets/images/blog/writers-are-performers-thumbnail.jpg</thumbnailImage>
    <thumbnailAlt>Visual representation of multidisciplinary writing as performance</thumbnailAlt>

    <!-- EXCERPT (Used in blog listings and previews) -->
    <excerpt>If you view writing as a performance, you realize you can write anything. Here's how I embraced being a multidisciplinary writer instead of limiting myself to one niche.</excerpt>

    <!-- FEATURED FLAG (Makes this post prominent on blog index) -->
    <featured>false</featured>

    <!-- TAGS (Categories for organization and filtering) -->
    <tags>
      <tag>Writing</tag>
      <tag>Content Marketing</tag>
      <tag>Professional Development</tag>
    </tags>
  </meta>

  <!-- POST CONTENT
       ======================================================================
       Content is wrapped in CDATA to allow HTML/CSS without XML parsing issues.

       AVAILABLE CSS CLASSES:
       - .lead           : Larger opening paragraph
       - .pullquote      : Centered, emphasized quote (use <blockquote>)
       - .callout        : Highlighted box for important content
       - <figure>        : Images with captions
       ====================================================================== -->
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
      <p class="lead">There is a peculiar anxiety that haunts writers who refuse to specialize.</p>

      <p>The conventional wisdom is clear enough: pick a lane, stay in it, become known for one thing. The algorithm rewards consistency. Recruiters want a clean narrative. LinkedIn profiles work best when they tell a single, legible story. And yet some of us keep wandering across boundaries anyway, writing technical documentation one month and narrative fiction the next, toggling between marketing copy and instructional design like we cannot decide who we want to be.</p>

      <p>For years, this felt like a professional liability. Then I encountered an idea that reframed everything: what if writing is not an identity but a performance?</p>

      <blockquote class="pullquote">
        If you view writing as a performance, you realize you can write anything.
      </blockquote>

      <p>This is not magical thinking. Performance is about learning the part. You study the world of the piece, the audience, the constraints, the rhythm, the stakes. You build a voice that fits the moment. The writer who can do this well is not unfocused; they are versatile in the way that a skilled actor is versatile, capable of inhabiting different roles without losing their craft.</p>

      <p>Consider how Michael Lewis approached <em>Moneyball</em>. He did not simply sit down and write a book about baseball statistics. He embedded himself in the world of the Oakland A's, learning Billy Beane's methods, his blind spots, his insecurities. He came to understand the human tension behind the numbers. Only then did he become the specific kind of narrator that story required. That process, the deep immersion followed by the careful construction of voice, is not just writing. It is role work.</p>

      <figure>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/writers-are-performers-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Visual representation of multidisciplinary writing as performance">
      </figure>

      <h2>The case for writing as performance</h2>

      <p>Once you start thinking of writing this way, something useful happens: the shame of not fitting into a single category begins to dissolve. If writing is performance, then a "writing style" is not your fixed identity. It is a role you can step into, develop, and set aside when the project ends.</p>

      <p>Different roles demand different things. Some require deep research and immersion, a kind of method acting where you live inside a system until you can translate it for someone else. Some are about precision and constraint, hitting your marks, cutting the fat, making each sentence do its job. Some are about emotion and timing, building tension, landing the beat, knowing when to let silence do the work. And some are about serving someone else's vision entirely, where you are not the star but the person who makes the story function.</p>

      <p>The writers who can move between these modes are not dilettantes. They are developing range.</p>

      <div class="callout">
        <p><strong>Roles a single writer might play:</strong></p>
        <ul>
          <li>Technical Writer</li>
          <li>Copywriter</li>
          <li>Storyteller</li>
          <li>UX Writer</li>
          <li>Content Strategist</li>
          <li>Scriptwriter</li>
          <li>Editor or Writing Manager</li>
          <li>Teacher or Trainer</li>
        </ul>
      </div>

      <h2>Range is transferable craft</h2>

      <p>Anyone who has watched a comedy actor deliver a devastating dramatic performance understands how skills transfer across contexts. Comedy teaches timing, cadence, subtext, misdirection, and restraint. Those same tools make dramatic work sharper and more human. The training in one domain enriches the other.</p>

      <p>Writing works the same way. Technical writing develops structure, clarity, audience empathy, and the discipline of constraint, skills that improve everything from personal essays to product announcements. Copywriting teaches attention and pacing; you learn how to earn the next sentence when every word costs money. Storytelling teaches stakes and momentum, the fundamental question of why anyone should care. Teaching develops the ability to scaffold information, to meet people where they are and guide them somewhere new.</p>

      <p>These are not disconnected specialties. They are different applications of the same underlying craft, and the writer who practices several of them is building a toolkit that compounds over time.</p>

      <h2>What multidisciplinary actually means</h2>

      <p>When writers describe themselves as multidisciplinary, the term can sound like a hedge, a polite way of admitting they have not figured out what they do. But there is a more useful interpretation.</p>

      <blockquote class="pullquote">
        Given the context, a trained writer can learn the part.
      </blockquote>

      <p>This means studying the audience, the goal, the constraints, the voice, and the stakes of each new project. It means stepping into the role that the moment requires rather than forcing every assignment into the same familiar shape. It means treating your career not as a single character you play forever, but as a repertoire you continue to expand.</p>

      <p>The algorithm may want one thing. Real creative lives rarely work that way.</p>

      <h2>What to expect from Everything Storyteller</h2>

      <p>This blog will explore the intersection of three areas: content strategy for writers who want their work to be understood clearly, storytelling craft for anyone trying to make work that lands, and honest reflection on what it takes to build a creative career without fitting neatly into a single box.</p>

      <p>Future posts will get more tactical, including how to position yourself as a writer with range without sounding vague, and how to build a professional identity that makes your variety make sense. If you have ever felt the tension between what the market wants and what your actual skills look like, this is a place to think through that problem together.</p>
    ]]>
  </content>
</post>
