<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <meta>
    <id>oathforger-chapter-1</id>
    <title>Oathforger - Chapter One</title>
    <subtitle>Epic Fantasy - Long form narrative sample</subtitle>
    <client>Master's Thesis</client>
    <role>Author</role>
    <thumbnail>/assets/images/oathforger-thumb.png</thumbnail>
    <teaser>The opening chapter of a long-form fantasy narrative written as a master's thesis project. Demonstrates voice, pacing, and world-building in fiction writing.</teaser>
    <tags>
      <tag>Narrative</tag>
      <tag>Content Writing</tag>
      <tag>Creative</tag>
      <tag>Writing Sample</tag>
    </tags>
  </meta>

  <summary>
  </summary>

  <content>
    <section>
      <heading>About This Sample</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <p style="font-size: 1.1rem; line-height: 1.6; color: #e0e1dd; max-width: 700px; margin: 0 auto 1rem;">Oathforger was my Master's Thesis novel, an epic fantasy exploring themes of freedom, family, and the weight of inherited trauma. This sample presents the opening chapter: "The Party Guest."</p>

          <p style="font-size: 1.1rem; line-height: 1.6; color: #e0e1dd; max-width: 700px; margin: 0 auto 1rem;">This chapter introduces Kohiri on the night she's invited to Revelry—a monthly celebration held by the Amethyst Circle, a group of Fae who tend the magical towers keeping their world safe. Having spent years training after being freed from slavery, Kohiri is finally being welcomed into the circle. The chapter explores her anxiety about belonging, her relationship with her rescuer Grimoak, and hints at approaching danger through distant horn calls that only she seems to notice.</p>

          <p style="font-size: 1.1rem; line-height: 1.6; color: #e0e1dd; max-width: 700px; margin: 0 auto 2rem;"><em>Click or tap to turn the page.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>

    <section>
      <heading>Chapter One: The Party Guest</heading>
      <body>
        <![CDATA[
          <style>
            .project__section:has(#book-container) h2 {
              text-align: center;
            }
          </style>
          <div id="book-container" style="max-width: 700px; margin: 0 auto; font-family: 'Georgia', serif; line-height: 1.8; color: #2a2a2a;">

            <!-- Page 1 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="1" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">The first sound that meant freedom to Kohiri was not a song or a prayer.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">It was the ring of iron links snapping, one after another, under Grimoak's sword.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Three years later, she still heard it sometimes when the springs were quiet and the night pressed close. Tonight, the waterfall muttered over stone and steam curled against her bare arms, yet that sound clung to her mind. Below, in the clearing, the circle gathered for Revelry. Lanternlight played across fur and wings, over rough-hewn tables piled with food and over faces that had never known a collar.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">The Fae held two things above all others: freedom and family. They might fight for many causes, shout themselves hoarse in favor of others, and find joy in a hundred small pleasures, but nothing had shaped their culture the way those two had. These virtues were not unique to the Fae, but no other people on Aularia clung to them so fiercely.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">The Fae weren't native to Aularia. They came from a world called Faeholme, a paradise where they once lived with their creator, Oenomaus. That was before the Abyssals came, ravaged their world, and enslaved the Fae for their magic. Oenomaus died to usher the Fae through a portal to the then-young world of Aularia, buying their freedom with his life. The towers they tended now were the bones of the ward he had left behind, dampening wild magic and keeping the Abyssals' claws from finding purchase under this sky.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">1</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 2 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="2" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">It was no surprise that family was so important as well. The Fae stuck together in families they made themselves. Circles. Bound together by oaths, promises to protect one another. To live freely with one another. To celebrate every day of freedom. To find a way to bring Oenomaus back, if it were even possible.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">These were the lessons that Kohiri had learned in the last year of her life from Fae that were much older than her, some by scores of years. Having recently turned twenty, she was barely an adult by Fae standards. Her kind weren't apt to release even young adults to the larger world, lest their naivety lead them to Daltanic cages or Casorian fighting pits. Few humans understood the Fae, least of all in the Daltanic Empire, but every forest needed a circle to tend to it. It was unfortunate that the Stardust Forest was in Daltanic territory, but the Fae of the Amethyst Circle made do. Having so many minotaurs among their ranks certainly helped. Even so, the last year had brought more Daltanic patrols along the forest edge. Kohiri had learned the clink of their armor and the rhythm of their marching the way other children learned birdsong. Lately, she had heard it more often than she liked.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri was no minotaur, and she often envied their bulk, their powerful digitigrade legs, six and a half foot stature, and majestic horns. She was a pixie, and she could pass for a human if not for her pointed ears and shimmering, pale blue, butterfly-like wings. Many ignorant humans thought pixies were tiny creatures, but Kohiri stood as tall as any full-grown human woman, her hair unerringly straight, strands of gold and light brown mixing together to frame her brown eyes and unpainted face.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">2</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 3 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="3" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">In place of freckles, a few blue sparkles dotted the bridge of her nose and under each eye. Her arms and legs were sinewy, her shoulders rounded, hands callused from a childhood spent training and climbing trees, along with a few scars from all the times she had fallen or been struck by an unexpected blow. Her wings could do little more than flutter, after all, and perhaps help her body to hover for a few labored seconds.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Unlike her, the minotaurs were born to fight. Even an untrained minotaur's strength was enough to give pause to the staunchest warriors of other races. Satyrs were much the same way. Pixies, on the other hand, weren't expected to pick up a sword, and yet a thin silver blade rested at Kohiri's side. Grimoak had taught her how to use it well in the past two years she had spent petitioning his circle, hoping they would accept her as a member.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">They had.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri watched freedom and family as the Fae saw it. There was no better time to observe it than during the festival of Revelry. Every month, the circle gathered together to honor Oenomaus' sacrifice with libations, dance, and merriment. It was the first Revelry that Kohiri had been to since she was a child, still small enough to hide behind the golden fur of her satyr father. She was not that shy girl anymore, but she didn't presume she should be anything more than observant as she watched from her place on a smooth-surfaced, steamy rock, with the flowing hot springs at her back.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">3</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 4 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="4" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">A satyr child tore past her, hooves skidding on the wet stone. One foot went out from under him, and he pinwheeled toward the steaming water. Kohiri moved before she had time to think, catching him by the wrist and hauling him back from the edge.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Careful," she said, more sharply than she intended.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">He blinked up at her with big green eyes, then grinned and bolted back toward the tables. No thanks, no sense of how close he had come. Kohiri shook the water from her hands and sat again, suddenly aware of how fast her heart was beating.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Beyond the spring, the clearing opened out before her, two rough-hewn oaken tables resting atop a thin bed of snow, disturbed in several places by boot and hoof marks. When Kohiri closed her eyes, she could feel the nearby tower's low hum in her bones, the way all Fae could when the warding stones were healthy.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">She watched Belra, a sour-faced gloaming woman, flutter her dark wings in annoyance as a young satyr plucked a rice ball off the platter she was carrying. The woman stopped in her tracks as he tossed it into the air and tried to catch it in his mouth, but couldn't help cracking a smile when it didn't fit and burst apart across his face. He furrowed his brow as he swallowed, perhaps not realizing that his beard was covered in flecks of melted cheese and rice.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">4</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 5 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="5" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">A roar of laughter went up at the far table, someone slamming a fist down hard enough to rattle the cups. Kohiri's shoulders jumped, her hand half-rising toward the hilt at her side. Then Belra, too, burst out laughing, and Kohiri caught herself, drawing her hand away from the sword. She struggled to remember when last she had seen a gloaming smile, let alone laugh. It seemed Revelry really did have its intended effect.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Koh, koh."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri's attention was stolen from the scene in front of her by a familiar voice from behind her, disrupting the constant that was the sound of the tiny waterfall pouring into the spring. Megwei, a pixie not too much older than her, was fluttering her wings and splashing her way through the spring. Kohiri twisted her body slightly to face her. Her short, red-pink hair was matted down and dripping while her wings fluttered, beading up with moisture like rain on glass.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Koh, you don't have to just sit there, you know," Megwei said, her voice so high she sounded ten years younger. "Have fun. It's Revelry."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"It's ok. I am just here to watch and have a hot meal," Kohiri replied, her response barely audible over the flowing water.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">5</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 6 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="6" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Are you nervous?" Megwei said, scrunching up her nose. "Oh Oenomaus help us! You're nervous. Grim, Koh is nervous!"</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri swiveled her head all the way around, not realizing that Grimoak was only steps away from the other side of the spring, seemingly approaching from the northern woods. He responded with a low grumble that rolled over the water's surface and left Kohiri's pointed ears vibrating uncomfortably. It made them itchy. Grimoak was the tallest minotaur Kohiri had ever met. His legs were as thick as his namesake. One of his horns was cracked and blackening, and his graying beard showed his late middle age. On his back he carried a sword so long and broad that it made Kohiri's look like a dagger. His dark skin contrasted starkly with the white snow.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Wouldn't you be nervous?" Grimoak said, his voice rumbling and low. If a tree could talk, Kohiri imagined Grim's voice would be what came out.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I never get nervous!" Megwei replied, spinning about in the water, as if to show how carefree she was.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"You were never invited to a Revelry before joining the circle," Grim said, beginning to circle the hot spring. Steam rolled about at the edge, leaving the charcoal fur on his right leg damp and curling.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">6</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 7 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="7" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Nervous isn't the word," Kohiri said. "I'm trying to be..." she paused, looking up to find the right way to phrase it. The clear night sky, filled with the light of so many other distant worlds, nearly distracted her yet again. "Respectful," she said quickly. "I want to be respectful."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Relax," Megwei said. "Nobody cares. Just have fun."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Grim shot Megwei a look, his teeth clenched behind his lips.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I... I'm ok," Kohiri said, "really. This is just how I am." Megwei was what most people expected pixies to be. She had grown up in the traditional pixie way. Her parents were members of the circle. When she was old enough, she spent her time with all of the other Fae that were born in spring, playing with arcane and nature magic, dancing in the moonlight, and whatever else children of the forest do. Kohiri had spent that same time on her own in the Badgerwood to the south, learning to escape House Savarrio's frequent hunting excursions. Her mother had been killed by a human on horseback from a hundred feet away, and her father had been gruesomely sliced across the chest by another rider's sword. The sight of that golden tabard with its purple horse head at the center was burned into her memory almost as strongly as the memory carried in her blood of Oenomaus being cleaved apart by an Abyssal general.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">7</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 8 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="8" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Every kind of Fae had a way of dealing with the memories. For most pixies, a carefree exterior kept the darkness at bay. Kohiri just didn't see the world the way her fellow spring-wings did.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"You've come a long way. You aren't the girl whose chains I shattered three years ago," Grim said, patting Kohiri's head with five thick fingers as he walked by. "But I'm going to eat. I suggest you do the same. There are several people here you haven't met yet."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Megwei climbed out of the spring behind Kohiri, her loose clothes dripping with warm water. Much of it splattered against Kohiri's wings, which forced her to a standing position. Megwei simply shrugged and produced a small flame in her hands, using its heat to keep her warm while she dried off. She took Kohiri's spot on the rock, as if nothing had happened.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri shook her head and let out an audible sigh of annoyance, then followed Grimoak to the seating area. As they approached, she felt not unlike she had in the last memory she had of Revelry, hiding behind her father. Another memory crowded in alongside it, unwelcome and sharp. Hooves on hard-packed earth. The thunder of riders drawing up short. The snap of bowstrings. Golden tabards with purple horse heads filling her vision as people she loved scattered and fell.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">8</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 9 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="9" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">For a heartbeat, the shout of someone laughing near the tables twisted into the barked orders of a Daltanic officer, and Kohiri's shoulders tightened. She forced herself to breathe, to remember the snow under her boots, the heat of the springs at her back, the safety of the circle's clearing. This was not the Savarrio estate. Not anymore.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Appropriately, Grim was the stand-in this time. She was right, though: the hesitance she felt was not nerves; it was plain anxiety. She felt like she was trying to rejoin a world she had not been a part of for most of her life. The humans of House Savarrio had taken that life from her when they turned her into a dancing servant girl for most of her youth. Grim's rescue led to three years of martial training so it would never happen again, but more importantly, it led to this second chance.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">She didn't want to screw it up.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Let's see her, then," came the voice of another pixie, this one short, middle-aged, with rosy cheeks that sagged ever so slightly past her jaw, deep crevices on her face accentuated by her overwhelming smile. She approached and squinted her eyes as she got closer, then hovered in front of Kohiri as if she were a specimen of plant she was cataloging. "I remember when I was that young."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"You were never that young, mom," the young satyr who had stolen the rice ball said, in between stuffing his mouth with truffles.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">9</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 10 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="10" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Keep eating and shut your trap, Bix!" the woman yelled, but her tone seemed only half-serious. "I swear. This one. All he does is eat. What am I supposed to do?"</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri wasn't sure if she was supposed to answer, but the long pause that accompanied the woman sticking her hands on her hips led her to open her mouth. She, admittedly, didn't know what she was going to say before she got interrupted.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Please tell me you own more clothes than this," the woman said, grabbing the faded blue cloth Kohiri had draped around herself. "It looks like a blanket. Oenomaus help us... is this a blanket?"</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"It's..." Kohiri didn't know what to say. "It's clothes?"</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Yes, it certainly is. But it isn't much more than that," the woman said with a grimace.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Should it be more than that?"</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I'm going to make sure you look good when you take your oath to join the circle," the woman said with a definitive nod. "It will be my gift to you. A dress."</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">10</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 11 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="11" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"A dress?" Kohiri asked.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Have you never had a dress before?" the woman asked. Before Kohiri could answer, the woman had wrapped her hands around her. "Oh, you poor thing."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri straightened her body at first, put-off by the hug, but after a moment or two, it actually started to feel alright. She loosened herself in the motherly embrace. It had been a long time since anyone had put their hands on her so completely without it being a part of her martial training or the open-palm slap of a Savarrio noble.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"She may look like one of yours on the outside Kinra, but she's hard like an Autumn," Belra said to the woman. "She's an acorn, not a flower petal."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"And how do you know?" Kinra said as she released Kohiri.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I've spoken to her plenty of times now," Belra said. The gloaming was the only one of her kind in the circle. They were much the same as pixies in appearance, save for their skin being paler and their wings being darker. Their demeanor matched this appearance. Gloaming rarely seemed happy about anything, and always seemed to have a pessimistic viewpoint. Kohiri had heard Belra call herself "pragmatic" before. Grimoak was close with Belra, and more than once the woman had appeared at her training sessions to work her magic, producing constructs out of shadow for Kohiri to test her skills against.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">11</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 12 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="12" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"She can fight," Belra said, "can't you, girl?"</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"We can always use more of that," came another voice, this time from a satyr seated at the table. He was using his dagger like a kabob, covered in an apple slice, a wedge of dripping white cheese, and what looked like a slice of pie. "Murkz."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri was beginning to wonder which questions she was supposed to answer. She felt completely on display.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I'm sorry, Murkz? Is that your name?" Kohiri said. "I'm Kohiri, and yes, I can fight."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"If she can fight, let her prove it," Murkz called, looking past her to Grimoak. He didn't seem to be joking.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Not tonight," Grimoak rumbled, though his hand had already found the hilt on his back. "Revelry is for full bellies, not bruises."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Still, a pair of minotaurs had already cleared a space between the tables, horns laughing as they circled each other with practice blades. Snow kicked up under their hooves as they traded a few quick blows, steel ringing just loud enough to make Kohiri's fingers twitch toward the hilt at her side.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">12</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 13 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="13" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">The satyr nodded and bit into the apple wedge, but continued to watch her with interest.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Well what's fighting got to do with wearing a dress?" Kinra said indignantly. Behind her, the tables were covered end-to-end with food. So many colors. It brightened up the otherwise muted appearance of the clearing.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Nothing," Belra said. "But maybe you should ask her if she wants a dress before you start making her one. She's a person, you know."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Well honey, do you want a dress?" Kinra asked.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I... can I fight in it?" Kohiri replied.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Well, hell if I know! I've never been in a fight that I couldn't solve with magic," Kinra said, "but I suppose I can figure something out."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"I'd be very grateful if you made me a dress, then," Kohiri said, and forced a smile. It wasn't that she wasn't happy to have a dress made for her; she just felt too overwhelmed by the awkwardness of the situation to put her emotions on display so easily. Grimoak watched her from his seat at the head of one of the tables, but seemed to at some point decide she was well enough on her own as he turned his attention to the satyr next to him.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">13</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 14 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="14" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">There were a lot of satyr and minotaur in the Amethyst Circle. There were three pixies in the clearing: Megwei drying herself near the rock, Kohiri, and Kinra. Belra was the only gloaming. All the other Fae at the Revelry were progeny of summer or winter, horned and hooved, and never far from their weapons. Perhaps the cold weather of the Spire Point made most winged Fae flutter elsewhere, or perhaps there was more to it. Either way, Kohiri didn't mind. She felt out of season as it was, and the hooved Fae would make far better sparring partners.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Have a seat, girl," Kinra said quietly. Kohiri hadn't realized that she was one of the few left standing, and quickly found a seat at the table. She could feel the droplets of water frosting up on her wings just in time for Megwei, who had put them there in the first place, to sit down next to her. Megwei flashed her a smile before covering her plate in fruit and truffles.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Belra had claimed the seat at the head of the other table, but remained standing as everyone else sat down. Somewhere beyond the treeline, a horn sounded faintly, carried thin on the cold air. Kohiri frowned and lifted her head, but the note did not come again. The others hardly seemed to notice above the chatter and the clink of cups.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;"><em>Probably a hunter's signal,</em> she told herself. <em>Or a caravan on the Daltanic road, too far to matter here.</em></p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">14</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 15 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="15" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">As everyone settled, the chatter faded and attention drifted toward Belra. When only the murmur of the hot spring remained, she began to speak.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Every month, we come out of hiding to celebrate Revelry, just as our ancestors had celebrated every week with Oenomaus on Faeholme," Belra said. Just the mention of Oenomaus' name stirred the faintest memories; echoes of what one of her ancestors had experienced, now living on in her and in all the seasonal Fae who walked Aularia. Their children would know it, and their children's children would know it: the pain of seeing their creator killed before their very eyes. "But we are not on Faeholme. Oenomaus is lost to us. The First Oath we promised to ourselves and to Oenomaus was that we'd find a way to one day bring him back. We gather with family to live as he would have wanted us to live, to remind ourselves of this Oath, to take time to separate ourselves from the painful memories of our enslavement among the Abyssals.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"We are the Amethyst Circle, tenders of the Stardust Forest. We keep the towers standing so the world does not drown in its own magic. We keep that magic in balance so the Abyssals cannot easily claw their way back into it. We protect one another. We enjoy every moment of our freedom. And we stay watchful," Belra added, her gaze briefly drifting toward the dark line of trees beyond the firelight, where Daltanic roads and keeps pressed too close to the forest.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">15</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 16 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="16" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">A few ears pricked up. That last line was new.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Now..."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Everyone's lips moved as they joined in concert with Belra. Two dozen voices filled the clearing.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"...with every breath, word, and deed, we search for a way to bring him back to us."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">There was near-silence again as Belra paused.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Two things that must be said before we continue our Revelry tonight. First, Kinra's son Bix has been accepted to train as a Cosantyr in the Beastglades. He will be leaving our circle. Cheers to Bix, my nephew. He will make a fine Fae Knight." Belra's expression remained neutral, but she lifted her cup, as did everyone else. Kinra threw her hands around the satyr, who stood from his seat to take in the praise. His smile hid the food he had packed in behind his teeth, leaving his cheeks stretched like a hamster.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Always eating," Kinra repeated, a joyful tear in her eye, "always eating."</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">16</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 17 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="17" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"But as one family member leaves us, we gain another. Five nights from tonight, we will join together for something we have not done in a long time. Duke Grimoak has seen fit to have a new member join our beloved circle. I have forged an oath, and Kohiri, our long lost kin, whose own circle was torn apart by wretched Daltanics, and who has been unable to enjoy the same taste of freedom we have, will be taking that oath. The Amethyst Circle will remain whole."</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri slowly rose to her feet, but she was not met with the cheering or clapping that had greeted Bix. As much as Belra's speech had made her feel included, the lack of response from the members of the circle left her feeling anxious yet again. She could feel the embarrassing cold sweat begin to form above her brow, and could not stop thinking about how she had a patch of moisture, brightly glistening in the moonlight, above her eyes. She dipped her head so that as many golden strands of hair as possible would fall to cover her face.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Kohiri, we are welcoming you into our family," Belra said. "In five nights, we will come together in this same clearing and together, you and I will formalize your oath. You will be a member of the Amethyst Circle."</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">17</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Page 18 -->
            <div class="book-page" data-page="18" style="background: #fafaf8; padding: 3rem 2.5rem; margin-bottom: 2rem; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); min-height: 500px; cursor: pointer; display: none;">
              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">"Th-thank you," Kohiri said. Her voice sounded small to her own ears. She nodded and tried to steady her breathing. <em>You will be a member of the Amethyst Circle. You will be a member of the Amethyst Circle. You will be a member of the Amethyst Circle.</em> She could not stop repeating it to herself in Belra's voice.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">At last, cups were raised, and a mighty cheer followed. Some of it, she knew, was for her.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Kohiri smiled.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">This time she did not have to force it.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">Far off, on the edge of hearing, the horn sounded once more. She could not tell from which direction. No one else turned their head.</p>

              <p style="text-indent: 2em; margin-bottom: 1.2em;">In five nights, she would stand in this same clearing and take her oath. Whatever waited beyond the trees would still be out there when she did.</p>

              <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem; color: #999; font-size: 0.9em;">18</div>
            </div>

            <!-- Navigation Controls -->
            <div id="book-navigation" style="display: flex; justify-content: space-between; align-items: center; margin-top: 2rem; padding: 1rem; background: #f0f0ed; border-radius: 4px;">
              <button id="prev-page" style="padding: 0.75rem 1.5rem; background: #2a2a2a; color: white; border: none; border-radius: 4px; cursor: pointer; font-family: 'Georgia', serif; font-size: 1rem; opacity: 0.5;">
                ← Previous
              </button>
              <div id="page-indicator" style="font-family: 'Georgia', serif; color: #666; font-size: 1rem;">
                Page <span id="current-page">1</span> of 18
              </div>
              <button id="next-page" style="padding: 0.75rem 1.5rem; background: #2a2a2a; color: white; border: none; border-radius: 4px; cursor: pointer; font-family: 'Georgia', serif; font-size: 1rem;">
                Next →
              </button>
            </div>

            <!-- End message (hidden by default) -->
            <div id="end-message" style="display: none; text-align: center; margin: 3rem 0 2rem; padding: 1.5rem; background: #f0f0ed; border-radius: 4px;">
              <p style="font-style: italic; color: #666; margin: 0 0 0.5rem;">End of Chapter One</p>
              <p style="margin: 0; color: #888; font-size: 0.9em;">~4,016 words</p>
              <button id="restart-button" style="margin-top: 1rem; padding: 0.75rem 1.5rem; background: #2a2a2a; color: white; border: none; border-radius: 4px; cursor: pointer; font-family: 'Georgia', serif; font-size: 1rem;">
                Read Again
              </button>
            </div>

            <script>
              (function() {
                const totalPages = 18;
                let currentPage = 1;

                const pages = document.querySelectorAll('.book-page');
                const prevBtn = document.getElementById('prev-page');
                const nextBtn = document.getElementById('next-page');
                const currentPageSpan = document.getElementById('current-page');
                const bookNav = document.getElementById('book-navigation');
                const endMessage = document.getElementById('end-message');
                const restartBtn = document.getElementById('restart-button');

                function showPage(pageNum) {
                  // Hide all pages
                  pages.forEach(page => {
                    page.style.display = 'none';
                  });

                  // Show the requested page
                  const targetPage = document.querySelector(`[data-page="${pageNum}"]`);
                  if (targetPage) {
                    targetPage.style.display = 'block';
                    window.scrollTo({ top: targetPage.offsetTop - 20, behavior: 'smooth' });
                  }

                  // Update page indicator
                  currentPageSpan.textContent = pageNum;

                  // Update button states
                  if (pageNum === 1) {
                    prevBtn.style.opacity = '0.5';
                    prevBtn.style.cursor = 'not-allowed';
                  } else {
                    prevBtn.style.opacity = '1';
                    prevBtn.style.cursor = 'pointer';
                  }

                  if (pageNum === totalPages) {
                    nextBtn.textContent = 'Finish';
                  } else {
                    nextBtn.textContent = 'Next →';
                  }

                  currentPage = pageNum;
                }

                function nextPage() {
                  if (currentPage < totalPages) {
                    showPage(currentPage + 1);
                  } else {
                    // Show end message
                    pages.forEach(page => page.style.display = 'none');
                    bookNav.style.display = 'none';
                    endMessage.style.display = 'block';
                    window.scrollTo({ top: endMessage.offsetTop - 20, behavior: 'smooth' });
                  }
                }

                function prevPage() {
                  if (currentPage > 1) {
                    showPage(currentPage - 1);
                  }
                }

                function restart() {
                  endMessage.style.display = 'none';
                  bookNav.style.display = 'flex';
                  showPage(1);
                }

                // Button click handlers
                nextBtn.addEventListener('click', nextPage);
                prevBtn.addEventListener('click', prevPage);
                restartBtn.addEventListener('click', restart);

                // Click on page to advance
                pages.forEach(page => {
                  page.addEventListener('click', function(e) {
                    // Only advance if not clicking a button
                    if (e.target.tagName !== 'BUTTON') {
                      nextPage();
                    }
                  });
                });

                // Keyboard navigation
                document.addEventListener('keydown', function(e) {
                  if (e.key === 'ArrowRight' || e.key === ' ') {
                    e.preventDefault();
                    nextPage();
                  } else if (e.key === 'ArrowLeft') {
                    e.preventDefault();
                    prevPage();
                  }
                });

                // Initialize - show first page
                showPage(1);
              })();
            </script>

          </div>
        ]]>
      </body>
    </section>
  </content>

  <outcomes>
    <outcome>4,016-word opening chapter demonstrating character voice, worldbuilding, and narrative pacing</outcome>
    <outcome>Established main character's emotional arc and introduced key themes of belonging and freedom</outcome>
    <outcome>Created tension through environmental details (distant horns) foreshadowing future conflict</outcome>
  </outcomes>
</project>
