<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <meta>
    <id>short-form-ugc-copy</id>
    <title>Podcast UGC-Style Ad Copy</title>
    <subtitle>Natural-language ad read in user-generated content style</subtitle>
    <client>Elgato</client>
    <role>Content Creator</role>
    <thumbnail>/assets/images/short-form-thumb.png</thumbnail>
    <teaser>This is an example of a natural-language ad read in the user-generated content style, focusing on a product that not only sponsored us, but that we actually used as part of our podcast production.</teaser>
    <tags>
      <tag>Product Writing</tag>
      <tag>Marketing</tag>
      <tag>Content Writing</tag>
      <tag>Creative</tag>
      <tag>Writing Sample</tag>
    </tags>
  </meta>

  <summary>
    This is an example of a natural-language ad read in the user-generated content style, focusing on a product that not only sponsored us, but that we actually used as part of our podcast production. It utilizes UGC testimonial style storytelling.
  </summary>

  <content>
    <section>
      <heading>Ad Copy</heading>
      <body><![CDATA[
<audio controls class="audio-player">
  <source src="/assets/audio/ugc-short-form-podcast-ad-read.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
</audio>

<div class="ad-copy-container">
  <p>Alright, quick break. This part is brought to you by Elgato.</p>

  <p>So, behind the scenes of Hatewatchers, it gets chaotic fast. We've got a four camera set up, three monitors, and a sound board with four mics.</p>

  <p>We're constantly switching camera angles, pulling up clips mid-interview, or playing audio clips. If you're our camera guy, you've got enough to worry about before you have to start messing with all of these tools.</p>

  <p>The Elgato Stream Deck has been our cheat code. It's just… buttons. Like, big, satisfying "press this and the thing happens" buttons. One tap and we swap cameras. One tap and the clip is up. One tap and the sound effect hits.</p>

  <p>No digging through menus, no "hold on, where is it," no dead air. Those buttons can control almost anything on your PC, so you can use it for even crazier things that we don't, like automatically clipping your best plays, running back a replay, or controlling your Voicemod tools.</p>

  <p>We're also using Elgato's capture card so we can run higher quality cameras instead of being stuck with basic webcams. The picture looks cleaner, more like an actual show, and the setup stays simple. I mean, you've seen it. How many people do you see live streaming with an output as crisp as ours?</p>

  <p>So if you're doing a podcast, streaming, YouTube, any of that, and you want your production to feel way more pro without making your life harder, check out Elgato's Stream Deck and their capture cards. We've got a link and code in the description.</p>

  <p>Thanks again to Elgato for supporting the Hatewatchers Podcast.</p>
</div>
      ]]></body>
    </section>
  </content>

  <outcomes>
    <outcome>Authentic testimonial-style copy that integrates product benefits with real production experience</outcome>
  </outcomes>
</project>
