<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<content>
  <section>
    <heading>The Everything Storyteller</heading>
    <body><![CDATA[
      <p>I'm a writer who works across content design, UX writing, technical documentation, 
      and narrative. I believe every piece of content, whether it's an error message or an epic fantasy chapter, 
      contributes to a product or customer's story.</p>
    ]]></body>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <heading>My Journey</heading>
    <body><![CDATA[
      <p>After getting my English Education degree at the University of Central Florida, I started my professional 
      career in the world of education, where I taught secondary school English and Creative Writing. While I found
      this to be satisfying work, my passion for writing pulled me in another direction. As I worked through my Masters 
      Degree in Creative Writing, the drive to do more than teach kept growing.</p>
      <p>I co-founded Sacred Grounds Gaming and served as the Director of Content, Narrative, and the Customer Experience.
      In this role, I juggled the business side while developing a massive amount of technical and creative content for a 
      unique business—live gamified experiences—with no clear blueprint to follow. It was a challenge that excited me and 
      sharpened my skills.</p>
      <p>I was directly responsible for much of Sacred Grounds' success, and the content I helped create allowed us to 
      successfully sell the intellectual property to another game company after nearly 7 years of development.</p>
      <p>In that role, I was a world-builder, marketer, policy writer, rules writer, director of talent, and narrative
      designer all-in-one. It was the foundation for my philosophy that "everything is a story", and that a good writer
      can be anything from a content designer to a novelist as long as they have the context, tools, and team behind them.</p>
      <p>I've been a part of Technical Content Experience at AWS, a POD leader for Google Search's XWF via Accenture, designed 
      trust and safety systems and story for social games, and created live gamified experiences that brought stories to life. 
      Each project reinforced my belief that good writing isn't about the medium; it's about understanding your audience and 
      meeting them where they are.</p>
    ]]></body>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <heading>What I Bring</heading>
    <body><![CDATA[
      <p>I bring narrative thinking to technical work: documentation and information architecture that guides rather than overwhelms,
      UI copy that is clear about what comes next, and content strategy that cares about not just what the customer needs, but 
      what will make them happy with their experience. And I bring technical rigor to creative work: structured approaches to world-building, 
      systematic thinking about user/player experience, and clear communication with cross-functional teams.</p>
      <p>Whether you need someone to make complex systems understandable, craft compelling user journeys, or write stories that resonate,
      I can help you tell it well.</p>
    ]]></body>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <heading>Beyond Work</heading>
    <body><![CDATA[
      <p>When I'm not writing, you'll find me out on hikes, walking my corgis, listening to an endless stream of audio books and podcasts, 
      or getting ready for my next D&D session. I'm a movie buff thanks to a minor in Film. I also love to learn by watching YouTube 
      tutorials or taking courses on various sites. I believe play and storytelling are fundamental to how we understand the world, 
      and that belief shapes everything I create.</p>
    ]]></body>
  </section>
</content>